Captain Vance provided training on traffic incident management,
including how to set up a traffic control zone
and use apparatus to block the scene.
The drill went smoothly,
but instead of completing the competency sheets,
he stacked them on his desk,
promising he'd finish them before the weekend.
He didn't.
The next week, one of his trainees responded to a traffic collision
and parked the apparatus incorrectly,
allowing a passing car to travel into the scene,
striking a firefighter and causing serious injuries.
After the incident, supervisors pulled the training files
to see whether the firefighter had been signed off.
Nothing.
No verifications.
No recorded deficiencies. No proof the skill was ever properly checked.
And to make matters worse, Stone, who had helped with that session,
had once again spent more time coaching his preferred firefighters
than ensuring everyone received equal instruction.